McCulloch, Frank Papers 5883
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series SERIES III: SPEECHES AND TESTIMONIES
  - Sub-Series A: Speeches By Frank McCulloch
    - McCulloch, Frank. "An Overview of the National Labor Relations Board: Perspectives Old and New, Controversial and Routine.", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      Industrial Relations Law and Behavior Seminar. University of Oklahoma. Norman, Oklahoma. 22 May 1969
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Trends, Constants, and Counter-Trends Under the National Labor Relations Act.", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      Collective Bargaining Forum. The Institute of Collective Bargaining and Group Relations. Waldorf-Astoria Hotel. New York City, New York. 12 May 1969
    - McCulloch, Frank. Remarks Before the Alabama Bar Association, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Tuscaloosa, Alabama. 19 July 1968
    - Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      Washington, DC, May 10
    - Supplemental Memorandum of the National Labor Relations Board to the Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers Committee on the Judiciary., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Labor Relations Reporter. 69. Washington: Bureau of National Affairs, Inc., 1968. *Note - this document accompanies the preceding entry - Frank McCulloch's Statement on May 10, 1968
    - The Role of the National Labor Relations Board and Its Relationship to Congress, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Subcommittee on the Separation of Powers of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate. Washington, DC March 29
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Past, Present and Future Remedies Under Section 8(a)(5) of the National Labor Relations Act.", 1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
      The Federal Bar Association and The George Washington University National Law Center Labor Relations Institute. Washington, DC. 15 February 1968
    - McCulloch, Frank. "New Remedies Under the National Labor Relations Act.", 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      New York University
    - S. 518, A Bill to Amend the Administrative Procedure Act., 1967 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Subcommittee on Administrative Practice and Procedure of the Committee on the Judiciary, United State Senate. Washington, DC. March 17
    - McCulloch, Frank, "Changing Labor Policies and Their Impact: The Scope of the Bargaining Obligation.", 1966 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      Thirty-Sixth Conference. Southern Economic Association. Atlanta, Georgia. 12 November 1966
    - Administrative Problems of the Board, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      Statement of Frank McCulloch before the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the Committee on Education and Labor. Washington, DC. February 9
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The Policy, the Purpose and the Philosophy of the NLRB as Revealed in Decision Trends.", 1965 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      Labor and Management: Partners in Progress. Texas Manufacturers Association 43rd Annual Conference of Texas Industry. The Inn of the Six Flags, Fort Worth - Arlington, Texas. 28 October 1965
    - McCulloch, Frank. Introductory Remarks to the Panel Discussion of "Your Company and the NLRB.", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      The Challenge of Change. NAM Sixty- Ninth Congress of American Industry. Waldor-Astoria, New York, New York. 3 December 1964
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Procedures Employed by NLRB in Determining Policy.", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      Administrative Law Section of the American Bar Association. Sheraton East Hotel, New York City, New York. 11 August 1964
    - McCulloch, Frank. "An Evaluation of the Remedies Available to the National Labor Relations Board - Is there Need for Legislative or Administrative Change?", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 17)
      Briefing Conference on Labor Management Relations. Federal Br Association Labor Law Committee. The Ambassador Hotel, Los Angeles, California. 13 June 1964
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The Consequences of NLRB Action on Good Faith Bargaining.", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      Seventeenth Annual Conference on Labor. New York University School of Law. The Barbizon-Plaza Hotel, New York, New York. 27 May 1964
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Recent Developments Affecting Arbitration and the NLRB.", 1964 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      Labor Arbitration Institute. Boston University School of Law. Boston, Massachusetts. 25 April 1964
    - McCulloch, Frank. "What Lies Ahead for Labor-Management Relations.", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      5th Annual Labor-Management Executive Luncheon. The Chicago International Trade Fair. Chicago Association of Commerce and Industry. Chicago, Illinois. 26 June 1963
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Compulsion and Freedom in Collective Bargaining.", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      Shulman Conference on Labor Relations. Yale Law School. New Haven Connecticut. 8 March 1963
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The Development of Administrative Remedies.", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      Midwest Seminar on NLRB Policy Changes. University of Chicago Center for Continuing Education. Chicago, Illinois. 2 February 1963
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Arbitration and/or The NLRB", 1963 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      National Academy of Arbitrators. Chicago, Illinois. 1 February 1963
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Federal Agency Lawyers and the Rule of Law.", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 24)
      October Dinner Meeting. Federal Bar Association (Chicago Chapter). Chicago, Illinois. 17 October 1962
    - McCulloch, Frank. "A Tale of Two Cities: Or Law in Action.", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 25)
      Labor Relations Law Section of the NLRB. Clift Hotel. San Francisco, California. 7 August 1962
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The NLRB in Action.", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 26)
      Eighth Annual Joint Industrial Relations Conference. Michigan State University. East Lansing, Michigan. 19 April 1962
    - McCulloch, Frank. Address to the Conference of Labor Editors., 1962 (Box 16, Folder 27)
      Washington, DC, 6 April 1962
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The How and Why of Recent NLRB Decisions.", 1962 (Box 16, Folder 28)
      Midwinter Personnel Conference. American Management Association. Chicago, Illinois. 15 February 1962
    - McCulloch, Frank. "New Problems in the Administration of the Labor-Management Relations Act: The Taft-Hartley Injunction", 1961 (Box 16, Folder 29)
      The Eighth Annual Institute on Labor Law. The Southwestern Legal Foundation. Dallas, Texas. 3 November 1961
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Developing Issues in Collective Bargaining.", 1961 (Box 16, Folder 30)
      Northern Minnesota Conference on Industrial Relations. Duluth, Minnesota. 19 October 1961
    - McCulloch, Frank. "Techniques For Expediting the Administrative Process.", 1961 (Box 16, Folder 31)
      Federal Bar Association Annual Convention of 1961. Mayflower Hotel, Washington, DC. 13 September 1961
    - McCulloch, Frank. "The Job of the National Labor Relations Board." (Box 16, Folder 32)
      No additional information provided
    - Remarks of Frank McCulloch at Swearing In and Assumption of Post of Chairman of the National Labor Relations Board (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Sub-Series B: Speeches by NLRB Officials
    - Index. S1 speeches given by NLRB officials, 1961-1965 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      Includes Author-Title Index and Subject Index
    - Brown, Gerald - Member of the NLRB, 1962-1968 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Cushman, Bernard - Special Assistant to the General Counsel, National Labor Relations Board, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Fanning, john - Member of the NLRB, 1962-1970 (Box 17, Folder 4-9)
    - Feldesman, William - Solicitor, NLRB, 1962-1968 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
    - Jaffe, Saul - Associate Solicitor, NLRB, 1965 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Kleeb, Howard - Associate Executive Secretary, NRB, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Leedom, Boyd - Member of the NLRB, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Ordman, Arnold - General Counsel, NLRB, 1963-1969 (Box 17, Folder 15-16)
    - Platt, Elihu - Assistant General Counsel to the NLRB, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Winkler, Ralph - Chief Counsel to NLRB Member Gerald Brown, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Zagoria, Sam - Member of the NLRB, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Speech Correspondence. Arranged chronologically, 1961-1970 (Box 17, Folder 20-24)
      Includes: letters of appreciation and thanks, program details, etc.
- Series SERIES IV: SUPPORTING PUBLICATIONS
  - Labor Relations Program, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    S.55 and S.J.Res.22. Part 4
  - Organization and Procedure of the National Labor Relations Board, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    S.es.66 and S.Res.141
  - Report on Regulatory Agencies to the President-Elect, 1960 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Reorganization Plan no.5 of 1961 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Administration of the Labor-Management Act by the NLRB, 1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Nomination Hearings on Frank W. McCulloch, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Questionnaire Survey on Delay in Administrative Proceedings, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Review of the National Labor Relations Act, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Administrative Procedure Act, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    S.518
  - To Amend the National Labor Relations Act to Increase Effectiveness of Remedies, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Congressional Oversight of Administrative Agencies (National Labor Relations Board), 1968 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Annual Report of the Director f the Administrative Office of the United States Court, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - National Labor Relations Act Remedies: The Unfulfilled Promise, 1968 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Labor Law Reform Study: Amendments to the Labor-Management Relations Act, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Separation of Powers and the Independent Agencies: Cases and Selected Readings, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Congressional Oversight of Administrative Agencies (National Labor Relations Board), 1970 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - District Court Jurisdiction Over Unfair Labor Practice Cases, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    S.3671
  - Amendments to Expedite the Remedies of the National Labor Relations Act, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    H.R.7152. 2 Copies.
  - United States, NLRB. Rules and Regulations and Statement of Procedures, Series 8 as amended., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Washington, DC.: US Government Printing Office
  - United States, National Labor Relations Board (NLRB). Hearing Manual Division of Trial Examiners., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    29-Mar-68
  - The Public Interest in National Labor Policy, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    (majority of research and writing done by George Shultz, George and Abraham Siegel). The Public Interest in National Labor Policy. New York: Committee for Economic Development
  - United States, NLRB. National Labor Relations Board Field Manual., 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    Revised edition, June 1971. Washington, DC.: US Government Printing Office
  - Leys, Wayne and Senn, Peter. Teaching Ethics in Labor Education, 1962 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Washington, DC.: The National Institute of Labor Education
  - Silverberg, Louis, ed. The Wagner Act: After Ten Years, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Washington, DC: The Bureau of National Affairs, Inc. Given to Frank McCulloch courtesy of Charles Whitmore, an exceptional trial examiner during McCulloch's terms on the National Labor Relations Board
  - McGuiness, Kenneth. The New Frontier NLRB., 1963 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Washington, DC: The Labor Policy Association, Inc.
  - United State, NLRB. NLRB Attorney's Manual, Division of Litigation, Appellate Court Branch (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - United States, NLRB, Office of the General Counsel. An Outline of Law and Procedure in Representation Cases, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    May-70
  - United States, NLRB. Regional, Sub regional, and Resident Offices, Historical Record, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Series SERIES V: TEACHING MATERIALS
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Includes: materials used by employer in connection with National Labor Relations Board election on February 4, 1972 at the UNIROYAL, Inc. plant, Farmville, Virginia.
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers (Box 20, Folder 2)
    Includes: union bulletins and leaflets from Stanley Furniture
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Includes: Hooker Furniture company bulletins and leaflets; union bulletins and leaflets
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    Includes: company leaflets from US Plywood Campaign, South Boston, Virginia
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    Includes: union leaflets from US Plywood Campaign, South Boston, Virginia
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Papermakers, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Includes: company leaflets and union leaflets from York Corrugated Containers campaign, Rock Hill, South Carolina
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7a)
    Includes: company materials from Portsmouth, Virginia plant, November 1971
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 7b)
    Includes: company materials from Portsmouth, Virginia plant, November 1971 - 2nd copy
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 8a)
    Includes: union leaflets from the last two weeks of the campaign at Portsmouth, Virginia plant, November 1971
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 8b)
    Includes: union leaflets from the last two weeks of the campaign at Portsmouth, Virginia plant, November 1971 - 2nd copy
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    Includes: National Labor Relations Board v. General Electric Company and International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers, AFL-CIO. United States Court of Appeals, Second Circuit, decided October 28 1969.; materials related to the case (news articles, GE press releases, issue summaries and analyses, memoranda, other items from GE's public relations campaign).
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Electric - IUE, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    Includes: letters and memoranda re: GE effort to enlist the American Civil Liberties Union in relation to National Labor Relations Board v. General Electric Company and International Union of Electrical, Radio, and Machine Workers, AFL-CIO. United States Court of Appeals, Second Circuit, decided October 28, 1969.
  - Election Campaign Materials - Stromberg-Carlson - CWA, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Includes: Company materials and 'Vote-No' Committee materials from Charlottesville, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - Stromberg-Carlson - CWA, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Includes: union materials (handbills, statistical information, etc.) from Charlottesville, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - Stromberg-Carlson - CWA, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Includes: Employer's Brief to Regional Director, Regional Director's Decision and Direction of Election, Charlottesville, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - GTE Sylvania - UE (United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America), 1973 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Includes: Special Bulletin announcing the election, company materials used at Greenland, New Hampshire plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - United Steelworkers of America (USWA), 1970 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    Includes: union materials from General Cable Corporation, KDI Electro-Tec Corporation, Roanoke Electric Steel Company, Roanoke, Virginia (it appears the campaign was held at General Cable Corporation in Buena Vista, Virginia)
  - Election Campaign Materials - General Cable Corporation - USWA, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    Includes: company materials from Buena Vista, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - Marco Oaks Industries - UAW, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 17)
    Includes: employer letters to employees, September-December 1971. Anaheim, California
  - Election Campaign Materials - Marco Oaks Industries - UAW, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 18)
    Includes: general UAW organizing materials sent from International Vice President of the United Automobile, Aerospace & Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW) in March 1972
  - Election Campaign Materials - Thiokol Chemical Corporation - Textile Workers Union of America, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Includes: company leaflets and letters, union leaflets and letters, and excelsior list. Waynesboro, Virginia
  - Election Campaign Materials - Alliance Manufacturing Company - IUE, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 20)
    Includes: union materials and employer letter to employees from Shenandoah, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - Carwood Manufacturing Company - Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    Includes: union letters and leaflets, employer letters and handouts to employees from Winder, Georgia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - Craddock-Terry Shoe Corporation - Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), 1968-1970 (Box 20, Folder 22)
    Includes: materials used by the union (esp. letters) and the company at the Lawrenceville, Dillwyn, Lynchburg and Farmville (Virginia) plants
  - Election Campaign Materials - Craddock-Terry Shoe Corporation - Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA), 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 23)
    Includes: company materials used at Farmville and Dillwyn plants
  - Election Campaign Materials - Stackpole Components Company - IUE, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 24)
    Includes: company and union materials from Farmville, Virginia plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - National Cash Register Company (NCR) - United Auto Workers (UAW), 1971 (Box 20, Folder 25)
    Includes: UAW handbills from Dayton Ohio plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - NCR - NCR Employees' Independent Union., 1971 (Box 20, Folder 26)
    Includes: Independent Union handbills from Dayton Ohio plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - NCR - IUE, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 27)
    Includes: IUE handbills from Dayton Ohio plant
  - Election Campaign Materials - NCR - UAW, IUE, Employees' Independent Union., 1971 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    Includes: company handbills from Dayton Ohio plant
  - Negotiation Materials - Stanley Furniture Company and United Papermakers and Paperworkers (Box 20, Folder 29)
    Includes: labor agreement between the company and the union, correspondence between the union and management
  - Negotiation Materials - Stanley Furniture Company and United Papermakers and Paperworkers, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    Includes: labor agreement between the company and the union, correspondence between the union and management. Stanley town, Virginia
  - Negotiation Materials - Stanley Furniture Company and United Papermakers and Paperworkers, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Supplemental Material - Southern Management, 1959-1965 (Box 20, Folder 32)
    Includes: Labor Analysis and Forecast, a semi-monthly newsletter to alert and inform Southern management on labor-relations and critical trends in trade and industrial unionism
  - Supplemental Material - Textile Workers Union of America (TWUA) (Box 20, Folder 33)
    Includes: The Hollow Promise, a publication of the TWUA; cases; news articles
  - Supplemental Material - Textile Workers Union of America and Reform of the Taft-Hartley Act (Box 20, Folder 34)
    Includes: cases, case summaries, fact sheets, table and graphs
  - Conspiracy in Southern Textiles, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 35)
    Includes: Conspiracy in Southern Textiles. Presentation of Textile Workers Union of America, AFl-CIO to the Special Subcommittee on Labor of the House committee on Education and Labor, Washington, DC. August
  - National Bituminous Coal Wage Agreement of 1968 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Castle Valley Mining Company - Official Report of Proceedings before the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Price, Utah. September 29, 1970
  - Castle Valley Mining Company - Official Report of Proceedings before the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB), 1970 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Price, Utah. September 30, 1970
  - Castle Valley Mining Company - Exhibits of Charging Party, General Counsel and Respondent, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Price, Utah. September 29-30, 1970
  - Castle Valley Mining Company - Brief for the Charging Party, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Unfair Labor Practice Case: Charge Against Employer, Board Order (Box 21, Folder 6-7)
  - Representation Case: Consent Agreement. (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
    Election Set Aside on Basis of Objections. Best Bet Foods
  - Charge Against Employer: Informal Settlement (Box 21, Folder 10-11)
    KINN Broadcasting
  - Representation Case: Hearing Followed by Directed Election and Certification of Results, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 12-13)
    Montgomery Ward & Co. Also Includes: Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board and Board Exhibits, March 15, 1971
  - Charge Against Employer (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Dismissed. Howard Electric Company
  - Representation Case: Stipulated Election, Hearing on Challenged Ballots with Board Order, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 15-17)
    Sierra Lingerie Company. Also Includes: Official Report of Proceedings Before the National Labor Relations Board and Board and Employer Exhibits. February 1972
  - Platt, Elihu - Assistant General Counsel to the NLRB, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Winkler, Ralph - Chief Counsel to NLRB Member Gerald Brown, 1963 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Zagoria, Sam - Member of the NLRB, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Gitelman, Morton. Unionization Attempts in Small Enterprises: A Guide for Employers, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Draft. Pp.1-119. Prepared by Duke University under a Small Business Administration Management Research Grant Program August 1961
  - Gitelman, Morton. Unionization Attempts in Small Enterprises: A Guide for Employers, 1961 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    Draft. Pp.120-End. Prepared by Duke University under a Small Business Administration Management Research Grant Program August 1961
  - United States. Civil Service Commission. Office of Director, Office of Hearing Examiners. Report of Advisory Committee for Hearing Examiners to United States Civil Service Commissioners, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    Jul-63
  - United States. Department of Labor, Bureau of Labor Statistics. Major Collective Bargaining Agreements. Management Rights and Union-Management Cooperation., 1966 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    Bulletin No. 1425-5. Washington, DC.: US Government Printing Office
  - Ross, Philip. The Labor Law in Action: An Analysis of the Administrative Process Under the Taft-Hartley Act., 1966 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    Sep-66
  - Macy, John W. "The APA and the Hearing Examiner: Products of a Viable Political Society.", 1967 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    Reprinted from Federal Bar Journal. Fall 1967
  - President's Review Committee. Report of the President's Review Committee on Employee-Management Relations in the Federal Service, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    Draft. April 1968
  - United States. Civil Service Commission. Announcement of examination for Hearing Examiner, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    also includes correspondence between Frank McCulloch, NLRB Chairman Edward Miller and Civil Service Commission Chairman Robert Hampton
  - Classified Index of National Labor Relations Board Decisions and Related Court Decisions, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    Jun-72
  - Classification Outline for Decision of the National Labor Relations Board and Related Court Decisions., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    Dec-72
  - United States. Office of Statistical Reports and Evaluation. Division of Administration. Agency Statistical Data Series, National Labor Relations Board, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    Mar-73